let datata = [
// "日"
{"answer": "こもれび", "question": "木漏れ日", "hint": "sunlightthrough"},
{"answer": "ひので", "question": "日の出", "hint": "sunrise"},
{"answer": "にっき", "question": "日記", "hint": "diary"},
{"answer": "まいにち", "question": "毎日", "hint": "everyday"},
{"answer": "ほんじつ", "question": "本日", "hint": "today"},
{"answer": "ようか", "question": "8日", "hint": "8thday"},
{"answer": "にほん", "question": "日本", "hint": "japan"},
{"answer": "きょう", "question": "今日", "hint": "today"},
{"answer": "あした", "question": "明日", "hint": "tomorrow"},
// "一"
{"answer": "いちばん", "question": "一番", "hint": "numberone"},
{"answer": "いっしょ", "question": "一緒", "hint": "together"},
{"answer": "ひとり", "question": "一人", "hint": "oneperson"},
{"answer": "ゆいいつ", "question": "唯一", "hint": "onlyone"},
{"answer": "おととし", "question": "一昨年", "hint": "yearbeforelast"},
// "人"
{"answer": "こいびと", "question": "恋人", "hint": "lovers"},
{"answer": "にんげん", "question": "人間", "hint": "human"},
{"answer": "じんせい", "question": "人生", "hint": "life"},
{"answer": "ひとりぐらし", "question": "一人暮らし", "hint": "livingalone"},
{"answer": "すけっと", "question": "助っ人", "hint": "helper"},
// "国"
{"answer": "ていこく", "question": "帝国", "hint": "empire"},
{"answer": "くに", "question": "国", "hint": "country"},
// "年":[
{"answer": "としごろ", "question": "年頃", "hint": "age"},
{"answer": "らいねん", "question": "来年", "hint": "nextyear"},
// "大":[
{"answer": "だいじょうぶ", "question": "大丈夫", "hint": "fine"},
{"answer": "たいへん", "question": "大変", "hint": "serious"},
{"answer": "おおきい", "question": "大きい", "hint": "big"},
{"answer": "おとな", "question": "大人", "hint": "adult"},
// "十":[
{"answer": "じゅうぶん", "question": "十分", "hint": "perfect"},
{"answer": "じゅっかい", "question": "十回", "hint": "10times"},
{"answer": "とおか", "question": "十日", "hint": "10thday"},
{"answer": "はつか", "question": "二十日", "hint": "20thday"},
{"answer": "みそじ", "question": "三十路", "hint": "agethirty"},
// "二":[
{"answer": "いっせきにちょう", "question": "一石二鳥", "hint": "onestone,twobird"},
{"answer": "ふたり", "question": "二人", "hint": "twopersons"},
{"answer": "ふつか", "question": "二日", "hint": "2ndday"},
{"answer": "はつか", "question": "二十日", "hint": "20thday"},
{"answer": "はたち", "question": "二十歳", "hint": "age20"},
// "本":[
{"answer": "にほん", "question": "日本", "hint": "japan"},
{"answer": "こんぽん", "question": "根本", "hint": "original"},
// "中":[
{"answer": "なかみ", "question": "中身", "hint": "inside"},
{"answer": "とちゅう", "question": "途中", "hint": "midst"},
{"answer": "いちにちじゅう", "question": "一日中", "hint": "alldaylong"},
{"answer": "みないうち", "question": "見ない中", "hint": "unnoticed"},
// "出":[
{"answer": "であい", "question": "出会い", "hint": "meeting"},
{"answer": "おもいだす", "question": "思い出す", "hint": "remember"},
{"answer": "だっしゅつ", "question": "脱出", "hint": "escape"},
{"answer": "さしだしにん", "question": "差出人", "hint": "sender"},
// "三":[
{"answer": "さんにん", "question": "三人", "hint": "threepeople"},
{"answer": "みつどもえ", "question": "三つ巴", "hint": "triplet"},
// "見":[
{"answer": "みる", "question": "見る", "hint": "watch"},
{"answer": "けんぶつ", "question": "見物", "hint": "sightseeing"},
// "月":[
{"answer": "おつきさま", "question": "お月様", "hint": "moon"},
{"answer": "こんげつ", "question": "今月", "hint": "thismonth"},
{"answer": "おしょうがつ", "question": "お正月", "hint": "lastmonth"},
{"answer": "せいねんがっぴ", "question": "生年月日", "hint": "DOB"},
// "長":[
{"answer": "かいちょう", "question": "会長", "hint": "councilpresident"},
{"answer": "ながびく", "question": "長引く", "hint": "prolonged"},
// "生":[
{"answer": "せいかつ", "question": "生活", "hint": "lifestyle"},
{"answer": "いきる", "question": "生きる", "hint": "live"},
{"answer": "うまれる", "question": "生まれる", "hint": "born"},
{"answer": "いっしょう", "question": "一生", "hint": "forever"},
{"answer": "たんじょうび", "question": "誕生日", "hint": "birthday"},
{"answer": "なまみ", "question": "生身", "hint": "raw"},
{"answer": "はえる", "question": "生える", "hint": "grow"},
{"answer": "きじ", "question": "生地", "hint": "fabric"},
// "五":[
{"answer": "ごもく", "question": "五目", "hint": "gomoku"},
{"answer": "いそじ", "question": "五十路", "hint": "agefifty"},
{"answer": "いつか", "question": "五日", "hint": "fifthday"},
// "時":[
{"answer": "じかん", "question": "時間", "hint": "time"},
{"answer": "いまどき", "question": "今時", "hint": "nowadays"},
{"answer": "ときのながれ", "question": "時の流れ", "hint": "flowoftime"},
{"answer": "とけい", "question": "時計", "hint": "clock"},
// "上":[
{"answer": "じょうず", "question": "上手", "hint": "skillful"},
{"answer": "うえ", "question": "上", "hint": "up"},
{"answer": "あげる", "question": "上げる", "hint": "raise"},
{"answer": "うわぎ", "question": "上着", "hint": "coat"},
{"answer": "のぼる", "question": "上る", "hint": "climbup"},
{"answer": "おかみ", "question": "御上", "hint": "empress"},
{"answer": "あげぷた", "question": "上蓋", "hint": "trapdoor"},
// "行":[
{"answer": "いく", "question": "行く", "hint": "willgo"},
{"answer": "りょこう", "question": "旅行", "hint": "travel"},
{"answer": "おこなう", "question": "行う", "hint": "perform"},
{"answer": "しゅぎょう", "question": "修行", "hint": "practice"},
{"answer": "ゆくえふめい", "question": "行方不明", "hint": "lostgoal"},
// "四":[
{"answer": "だいよん", "question": "第四", "hint": "fourth"},
{"answer": "しがつ", "question": "四月", "hint": "april"},
{"answer": "よにん", "question": "四人", "hint": "fourpeople"},
{"answer": "よっか", "question": "四日", "hint": "fourthday"},
{"answer": "よつや", "question": "四矢", "hint": "fourarrows"},
// "後":[
{"answer": "こんご", "question": "今後", "hint": "fromnowon"},
{"answer": "のちのち", "question": "後々", "hint": "timetotime"},
{"answer": "こうはい", "question": "後輩", "hint": "junior"},
{"answer": "うしろ", "question": "後ろ", "hint": "behind"},
{"answer": "あともどり", "question": "後戻り", "hint": "retrace"},
{"answer": "たちおくれ", "question": "立後れ", "hint": "slowstart"},
// "金":[
{"answer": "しょうきん", "question": "賞金", "hint": "prizemoney"},
{"answer": "かねもち", "question": "金持ち", "hint": "rich"},
{"answer": "おうごん", "question": "黄金", "hint": "golden"},
{"answer": "かなものや", "question": "金物屋", "hint": "goldshop"},
// "前":[
{"answer": "あたりまえ", "question": "当たり前", "hint": ""},
{"answer": "いぜん", "question": "以前", "hint": ""},
];

let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
function showQuestion() {
    const currentQuestion = datata[currentQuestionIndex];
    document.getElementById("Question").textContent = currentQuestion.question;
}

const myForm = document.getElementById("myForm");
myForm.addEventListener("submit", (event) => {
    event.preventDefault();
    const currentQuestion = datata[currentQuestionIndex];
    const formData = new FormData(myForm);
    const Answer = formData.get("Answer");
    if (Answer.toLowerCase() == currentQuestion.answer.toLowerCase()) {
        currentQuestionIndex++
        showQuestion();
    }else{
        document.getElementById("Question").textContent = currentQuestion.question + "\n(" + currentQuestion.hint + ")";
    }
})
showQuestion();

const mySkip = document.getElementById("mySkip");
mySkip.addEventListener("click", (event) => {
    currentQuestionIndex++
    showQuestion();
})
